Welcome back aliens my name is Devon Reddy and in this video we're going to talk
about
core Java.
In this particular course which is a lengthy video you're going to learn
everything from
the basics of core Java to the end of core Java.
Now this is not the first time I'm uploading the video on Java.
If you can see from last few years you will find multiple Java playlist and
multiple
Java full-fledged video.
But we all know right the quality of videos are going up every day plus the
number of features
getting added to a language is going up and that's the reason I'm going to re-
record
the entire course.
Now this is a full-fledged course and that's why it's so lengthy but you cannot
finish
the entire course in one day even if it says to 12 hours or 13 hours it will
take time.
Now let's talk about Java.
Now why Java is so famous?
Now if you see the programming index the top 5 programming language you will
always find
Java there maybe at the first position or at the fourth position you will find
Java.
Why Java is so famous is because Java has multiple features which helps it to be
used in
the enterprise market.
I mean not just enterprise market it can be used for mobile development web
development
and of course enterprise application.
And most of the big companies if you go there they are using Java as their
preferred language.
Now in Java we have a technology called JVM and it's not just Java we have
multiple languages
running on JVM.
So even if you are working on some other language let's say Kotlin, Scala,
Groovy,
ultimately you are working on Java technology and that's why if you learn core
Java it is
much easier for you to jump to different languages.
And I have also observed irrespective of which interior you are going for.
It can be for development or testing and that doesn't matter which language you
are working
on there.
Maybe Python, C sharp, C++.
They might ask you Java questions because most of the interior questions are
based on Java
because they feel that if you know Java that means you know other languages as
well or
you can learn other languages easily.
As for my experience or did I forgot to introduce myself?
My name is Evan Reddy I am a corporate trainer, software developer and currently
focusing
more on blockchain but Java is my first love.
So I am working on Java from last 12 years.
I've made multiple courses on Java on YouTube and different platforms and yeah I
can
teach Java any day, any time.
Yeah, sometimes I have to watch my own videos today wise the concept but the
thing is I
love Java and with this experience I am making the entire course.
I was talking about my experience right.
In fact I have learned multiple languages in this all 12 years.
Maybe I have worked on 12 different languages.
You can name it maybe C++, C Python, Java, JavaScript, Go language.
So I love most of the languages.
Some languages I learned just for the projects.
But then when I was learning those languages I was feeling hate it's so easy.
It's because I have learned Java.
Yes people say Java is difficult.
Yes to start with it is difficult.
Maybe if you want to learn Java is your first language.
It kind of difficult because if you are coming from other languages let's say
Python or
JavaScript and if you want to print one statement you can actually see that in
one line.
That's not the case with Java.
You have to write five lines of code.
Once you make a big application the number of lines will remain almost same.
So Java is difficult.
Yes it is to start with but the thing is Java is one of the most readable
language.
What I mean by that is if you are looking at someone else code you can read the
Java code
line by line.
That's not true with other languages.
So Java is great in that terms.
Java is maintainable and maybe that's why they most of the industries are
preferring
to use Java.
Now Java has multiple features.
We'll talk about those features later but just to name them we got what I which
is right
once run anywhere.
It supports multiple multithreads.
It has a collection API concept.
You can handle the exceptions and we are going to learn everything in this
particular course.
Now just to go for the history of Java Java was made in 1995 by Son Maccosystem
and it
was led by the team of James Gosling later on Oracle bought sons and now the
trademark
of Java belongs to Oracle.
Just in between Oracle did some messed up things with Java but yeah they are
back on track
and the beauty is Java is getting updated in every six months.
Not the major updates but they are working hard to make Java as the most
powerful language.
So I hope you were excited for the entire course.
We are going to start from the basic as I mentioned and you will learn a lot of
different
stuff.
But as I mentioned it's not about completing the entire course in one day.
You can use a timeline to jump between these sections and also with this we also
have
a code there.
So in the description you will find the link, GitHub link where you can access
all the codes
and maybe it will be helpful for you to write this code.
So let's start the journey.